<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The publick grievances of the nation adjudged necessary, by the Honourable the House of Commons, to be redressed.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Parliament. House of Commons.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A56241</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99831067</idno>
  <idno type="VID">35529</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240913580</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing P4154A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R219608</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99831067</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99831067e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A56241)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 35529)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2038:34)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The publick grievances of the nation adjudged necessary, by the Honourable the House of Commons, to be redressed.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament. House of Commons.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Edinburgh? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Re-printed in the year, 1689]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place of publication conjectured by Wing; date from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  William and Mary, 1689-1702 --  Sources --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1689-1702 --  Sources --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="list_of_grievances">
            <pb facs="tcp:35529:1"/>
            <head>The Publick <hi>GRIEVANCES</hi> of the NATION, Adjudged Necessary, by the Honourable the House of COMMONS, <hi>To be Redressed.</hi>
            </head>
            <list>
               <item>1. THat the pretended Power of Dispencing or Suspending of Laws, or the Execution of Laws, by Regal Prero<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gative, without consent of Parliament, is Illegal.</item>
               <item>2. The Commission for Erecting the late Court of Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioners for Ecclesiastical Causes, and all other Commissions and Courts of like Nature, are Illegal.</item>
               <item>3. Levying of Money for, or to the use of the Crown, by pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence of the Prerogative, without grant of Parliament, for longer time, or other manner than the same shall be so grant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, is Illegal.</item>
               <item>4. It is the Right of the Subjects to Petition the King, &amp; all Commitments &amp; prosecutions for such Petitioning, are Illegal 5. The Acts concerning the Militia are grievous to the subject.</item>
               <item>6. That the raising or keeping a standing Army within this Kingdom, in time of peace, unlesse it be with consent of Parliament, is against Law.</item>
               <item>7. 'Tis necessary for the publick safety, that the Subjects which are Protestants should provide and keep Arms for their common Defence, and that the Arms which have been seiz'd and taken from them, be restored.</item>
               <item>8. The Right and Freedom of Electing Members of the House of Commons, and the Right and priviledges of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament and members of Parliament, as well in the Inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vals as during their sitting, be preserved.</item>
               <item>9. That Parliaments ought to sit frequently, and that their frequent sitting be secured.</item>
               <item>10. No interruption of any session of Parliament, till the Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fajrs which are necessary to be dispatched at that time be deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined.</item>
               <item>11. The too long continuance of the same Parliament to be prevented.</item>
               <item>12. No pardon to be pleadable to an Impeachment in Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament.</item>
               <item>13. Cities, Vniversities, Towns Corporate, Boroughs and Plantations to be secured against <hi>Quo-Warranto's, Surrenders,</hi> and <hi>Mandats,</hi> and Restor'd to their ancient Rights.</item>
               <pb facs="tcp:35529:2"/>
               <item>14. None of the Royal Family to marry a Papist.</item>
               <item>15. Every King &amp; Queen of the Realm at the time of the entring into the Exercise of their regal Authority, to take an oath for the maintaining the Protestant Religion, &amp; the Laws and Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties of this Nation, &amp; that the Coronation Oath be reviewed.</item>
               <item>16. Effectual provision to be made for the Liberty of the Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stants in the exercise of their Religion, &amp; for the uniting all Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>testants in the matter of publick Worship as far as may be.</item>
               <item>17. Constructions upon the Statutes of Treason, and Try<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>als, and Proceedings, and Writs of Error in Cases of Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son, to be Regulated.</item>
               <item>18. Iudges Commissions to be made <hi>Quam dieu se bene gesse<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rint,</hi> and their Salleries to be ascertained and established to be paid out of the publick Revenue only, and not to be removed or suspended from Execution of their Office, but by due course of Law.</item>
               <item>19. The requiring excessive Bail of persons committed in criminal cases, and imposing excessive Fines and illegal pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nishments, to be prevented.</item>
               <item>20. Abuses in the appointing of Sheriffs, and in the execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of their Office, to be reformed.</item>
               <item>21. Iurors to be duly Impanelled and return'd, and cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt and false Verdicts prevented.</item>
               <item>22. Informations in the Court of <hi>Kings Bench</hi> to be taken away</item>
               <item>23. The <hi>Chancery</hi> and other Courts of Iustice, and the Fees of Officers, to be Regulated.</item>
               <item>24. That the buying and selling of Offices be effectually provided against.</item>
               <item>25. That upon Returns upon <hi>Habeas Corpus'es,</hi> &amp; <hi>Mandamus'es,</hi> Liberty be given to the Subject to Traverse such Returns.</item>
               <item>26. That all Grants and Promises of Fines and Forefeitures are illegal and void, and that all such persons as procure them, to be lyable to punishment.</item>
               <item>27. That the Abuses and Oppressions in Levying and Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lecting the <hi>Hearth-Money,</hi> be effecually Redressed.</item>
               <item>28. That the Abuses and Oprressions in Levying and Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lecting the Excise, be effectually Redressed.</item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Re-printed in the Year, 1689.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>